<?xml version="1.0"?>
<opml version="2.0">
	<head>
		<title>2024-12</title>
		<dateCreated>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 14:10:51 GMT</dateCreated>
		<dateModified>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 14:12:56 GMT</dateModified>
		<ownerId>frank.mcpherson@gmail.com</ownerId>
		<urlUpdateSocket>wss://drummer.land/</urlUpdateSocket>
		<ownerName>Frank McPherson</ownerName>
		<ownerEmail>frank.mcpherson@gmail.com</ownerEmail>
		<expansionState>1</expansionState>
		<lastCursor>1</lastCursor>
		</head>
	<body>
		<outline text="December 2024" created="Mon, 02 Dec 2024 14:29:50 GMT" name="december2024" type="calendarMonth">
			<outline text="December 26" created="Thu, 26 Dec 2024 20:34:31 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="26">
				<outline text="Remember eating pizza for lunch when I was in high school, and I remember that pizza being in squares, but I don't know whether &lt;a href=&quot;https://kottke.org/24/12/how-to-make-80s-school-cafeteria-pizza&quot;&gt;this was the recipe&lt;/a&gt;, but it's seems probable." created="Thu, 26 Dec 2024 21:00:40 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Yesterday (Christmas day) is the first time that Netflix streamed live NFL games and I was happy to have a sports alternative to the NBA, which historically has been the only professional league playing on Christmas. Netflix's production did not go without a hitch for me using an Apple TV. I went in to the app and selected &quot;Watch Live&quot; which I expected would take me to whatever was the current place of the stream, but instead it started at the beginning of the stream an hour earlier. Worse, for some reason it got to a point where it just kept showing non-stop commercials, like it was stuck in a loop. I was screaming in frustration/anger because I knew the game had started and I was not able to watch it. It then dawned on me to look at the progress indicator at the bottom of the display and I noticed it mostly at the beginning on the left rather than the right, so I tried fast forwarding and that enabled me to catch up. I don't know what happened, I searched to see whether anyone else had the same experience and &lt;a href=&quot;https://tvanswerman.com/2024/12/26/the-nfl-on-christmas-how-did-netflixs-picture-look-did-it-buffer/&quot;&gt;I did not find any reports&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 26 Dec 2024 20:34:32 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 20" created="Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:17:28 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="20">
				<outline text="I've decided to give &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsidian.md&quot;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt; another go. I have paid for one year of Obsidian sync and I have set up sync with my iPad Mini and Pixel 7a. On both devices I excluded sync of my Evernote import and on the phone I also excluded my Readwise import. Sync to the iPad took all night." created="Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:25:20 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Last work day of the year. I am about to start a period of two weeks of &quot;vacation&quot; and I don't normally take more than one week off at a time. Last night my wife asked if I had a to do list for this time. Some times I do make a list of projects for my time off that I usually don't complete." created="Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:17:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Major League Hypocrisy" created="Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:26:21 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I have a reflexive reaction to hypocrisy and that reflex is often triggered by Major League Baseball. Ever since Sammy Sosa left the Cubs in 2004 he has been not welcomed by the Chicago Cubs, mostly because of ownership's &quot;holier than thou&quot; attitude toward Sammy's use of performance enhancing drugs. Sammy's place in Cubs history and his alumni status were not to be recognized until he apologized. The hypocrisy is that every part of MLB, from ownership, the commissioner, the media, and the players knew who was taking PEDs and looked the other way for sake of all the money rolling in from the coverage of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.espn.com/mlb/story/_/id/29251553/the-mcgwire-sosa-home-run-chase-helped-make-1998-one-mlb-wildest-seasons-ever&quot;&gt;Sammy and Mark McGwire's season home run race in 1998&lt;/a&gt;. The fact that race re-engaged a pissed off fan base due to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1994%E2%80%9395_Major_League_Baseball_strike&quot;&gt;the players strike during 1994-95&lt;/a&gt;, which lead to millions of more dollars for all involved, seems lost on everyone." created="Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:17:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleedcubbieblue.com/2024/12/19/24325246/sammy-sosa-apologizes-2025-cubs-convention&quot;&gt;So, Ricketts got his apology yesterday&lt;/a&gt;, and so all is forgiven and they look forward to seeing Sammy at the upcoming Cubs convention. Sure they would, like the &quot;incident&quot; itself, Sammy's participation in that convention will result in more money for all involved. Question, when is Mr. Ricketts going to apologize to Cubs fans for the poor product he has been putting on the field the last seven years? " created="Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:27:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="As a fellow human being, Sammy Sosa deserves forgiveness and grace given to him for mistakes he made in the past, but is forgiveness only &quot;given&quot; upon condition truly forgiveness? Sosa, McGwire, Bonds and all the others could have been &quot;better&quot; humans, but like so many of us they gave in to the temptations and expectations put upon them. But, all of these players were and are being scapegoated by a corrupted system that wants our attention on them while the powers of the system put more money in their pocket. " created="Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:30:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="Let's see an apology from the MLB baseball commissioner on behalf of the league and ownership for the culture they nurtured during the &quot;PED era.&quot; As reconciliation, they can figure out how the hall of fame can recognize the good and the bad of these players as well as what was done to them. Further, a league that has gone all in on gambling really has no high ground to keep Pete Rose out of the hall of fame. " created="Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:36:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 18" created="Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:07:55 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="18">
				<outline text="Generations of people in the United States have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/28/opinion/trump-values-maga-cabinet.html?unlocked_article_code=1.dk4.6615.SsTomqZvz3j9&amp;smid=url-share&quot;&gt;grown up under the thumb of institutions&lt;/a&gt; that they believe are corrupt. The only solution now, these people believe, is to blow up the institutions. The focus is on the destruction of the institutions with little thought about what comes next. Who decides what comes next and why? This is the opportunity the billionaire class sees for themselves, which is why people like Elon Musk are willing to &quot;donate&quot; their time go the new U.S. Presidential administration." created="Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:40:27 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Now that Android has a setting to stop charging after it reaches 80% I am using the Pixel Stand more and now I wish it had more features. Like, while the Phone is in the stand it would be cool if I could access Favorites in Google Home. And why should the phone be locked when it's in the stand? There is actually a Bluetooth connection between the stand and the phone. " created="Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:07:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 16" created="Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:29:14 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="16">
				<outline text="Created some new &lt;a href=&quot;https://frankmcpherson.blog/photo-collections/&quot;&gt;photo collections&lt;/a&gt; to my blog using the new feature that Manton added to micro.blog. " created="Mon, 16 Dec 2024 15:19:37 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The season is truly upon us as the Manheim Christmas has come up on the music rotation." created="Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:29:15 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 13" created="Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:32:11 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="13">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.espn.com/college-football/schedule/_/week/1/year/2024/seasontype/3?ex_cid=ESPN-Email-20241213-DM58006-CFB%20COBM&amp;cid=ESPN-Email-20241213-DM58006-CFB%20COBM&amp;deliveryName=DM58006&quot;&gt;The annual college football bowl games&lt;/a&gt; begin tomorrow despite the college football playoffs that don't start until next Friday. I don't recognize most of the bowl game names, but I am intrigued by &lt;a href=&quot;https://thearizonabowl.com/&quot;&gt;the Snoop Dog Arizona Bowl&lt;/a&gt; that Colorado State plays in on December 28, 2024." created="Fri, 13 Dec 2024 17:00:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I have long believed that &lt;a href=&quot;https://finance.yahoo.com/news/former-aetna-ceo-says-d-094300416.html&quot;&gt;health insurance should not be tied to one's employment&lt;/a&gt;, because that creates problems whenever some is let go or quits. A public marketplace like that provided under the Affordable Care Act that can provided group discounted rates is the only one that makes sense if you don't provide a government program like Medicare for all. " created="Fri, 13 Dec 2024 16:01:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Did the Pixel 7a charging status always show the time by which charging would be complete? " created="Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:32:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 12" created="Thu, 12 Dec 2024 16:20:00 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="12">
				<outline text="Seems to me that if Evangelicals truly followed the teachings of Jesus they would oppose Republican and Democrat &lt;a href=&quot;https://pluralistic.net/2024/12/11/nimby-yimby-fimby/&quot;&gt;policies that turn homeless people in to criminals&lt;/a&gt;. They would &lt;b&gt;strongly&lt;/b&gt; oppose to the idea of profits at the expense of life, for example they would &lt;b&gt;strongly&lt;/b&gt; oppose a for profit health care system that puts profits over lives. You know, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Matthew%2025%3A40-45&amp;version=NIV;KJV&quot;&gt;whatever you do to the least of these you to do to me&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 12 Dec 2024 16:33:24 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Last night when I turned on the TV the set top box that Xfinity provides would not turn on. The chatbot in the Xfinity app guided me through some simple troubleshooting, tried a remote reset, and then scheduled a technician to come when it could not resolve the issue. Not sure why a technical needs to be dispatched, I would think Xfinity would simply send me a replacement set to box." created="Thu, 12 Dec 2024 16:28:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Installed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5google.com/2024/09/12/android-15-qpr1-beta-2-everything-new/&quot;&gt;Android 15 QPR 1&lt;/a&gt; update on my Pixel 7a yesterday. The most important new feature for me is the 80% limit on recharging the phone. Information I've seen about phone battery life suggests that continually charging the phones up to 100% has a big impact on battery life. I think that problem is made worse by wireless charging that makes it simple to just recharge the phone whenever it is not in my pocket. For example, I have the &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.google.com/product/pixel_stand_2nd_gen?hl=en-US&quot;&gt;Pixel Stand&lt;/a&gt; that really seems intended to be the resting space for my phone when I am at my desk, but before yesterday I had to be sure to not leave it on the stand once the battery reached 80% or so of charge. Now I (hopefully) no longer have to worry about that. " created="Thu, 12 Dec 2024 16:20:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 11" created="Wed, 11 Dec 2024 14:11:26 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="11">
				<outline text="Was seeing a problem of a pause while &lt;a href=&quot;https://info.frankmcpherson.net/whatIsFrankDoing.opml&quot;&gt;my Now page&lt;/a&gt; is rendering. Looking at the browser console, there appeared to be a problem reading my glossary.opml, which doesn't work with pagePark. At one time I added the glossary variable to the OPML headers of that file, but I have now deleted that and that appears to have resolved the issue.  " created="Wed, 11 Dec 2024 14:11:27 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="BTW, it would be really cool if the glossary did work with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/pagePark&quot;&gt;pagePark&lt;/a&gt;." created="Wed, 11 Dec 2024 14:30:02 GMT"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 5" created="Thu, 05 Dec 2024 14:17:15 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="05">
				<outline text="A few weeks back I started using &lt;a href=&quot;https://arc.net&quot;&gt;Arc&lt;/a&gt; as my default browser on the Macbook, I have to admit that I am enjoying the experience very much. I am probably just scratching the surface of the features. I can see why people have been praising it for so long." created="Thu, 05 Dec 2024 19:59:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="It's cold outside, windchill is driving the feels like temperature to 3 degrees, due to 16 mph sustained wins and gusts up to 38 mph. Snow squalls were all around us overnight but I think we got an inch of snow, at most. " created="Thu, 05 Dec 2024 14:17:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 4" created="Wed, 04 Dec 2024 14:00:09 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="04">
				<outline text="Isn't a chatbot nothing more than a command line interface? In some ways AI is taking us back to the future." created="Wed, 04 Dec 2024 15:27:03 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://adventurelog.app/docs/intro/adventurelog_overview.html&quot;&gt;AdventureLog&lt;/a&gt; is a self hosted travel log, and there is a Proxmox helper script to run it in an LXC container." created="Wed, 04 Dec 2024 14:41:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Followed &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5google.com/2024/12/03/gemini-app-utilities-extension/&quot;&gt;these steps&lt;/a&gt; and the Utilities extension is enabled in Gemini on my Pixel 7a. With this extension it looks like Gemini has taken over much of the functions from Google Assistant.  " created="Wed, 04 Dec 2024 14:00:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="December 2" created="Mon, 02 Dec 2024 14:29:51 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="02">
				<outline text="The posts that I write and publish to micro.blog are cross-posted to Bluesky and Mastodon. Up until now that has been one way, but now I can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.manton.org/2024/12/01/mastodon-replies-in.html&quot;&gt;see replies from either in my micro.blog mentions&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Mon, 02 Dec 2024 16:37:40 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I've created a new wiki page for the Macbook Pro M4. I need to make updates in the wiki and move it to a new server. " created="Mon, 02 Dec 2024 15:40:19 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Back to work after a nice four day weekend that happened to include Thanksgiving, plenty of food, Packers and Lions wins, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?gs_ssp=eJzj4tVP1zc0LLHMzYg3Ki8zYPTiKclIVUhLzMlRSC-tBACDqQk7&amp;q=the+fall+guy&amp;oq=the+fall+guy&amp;gs_lcrp=EgZjaHJvbWUqCggBEC4YsQMYgAQyBwgAEAAYjwIyCggBEC4YsQMYgAQyBwgCEAAYgAQyCggDEC4YsQMYgAQyBwgEEAAYgAQyCggFEAAYsQMYgAQyBwgGEAAYgAQyBwgHEAAYgAQyBwgIEAAYgAQyBwgJEAAYjwLSAQg0Njk1ajBqN6gCALACAA&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8&quot;&gt;a movie&lt;/a&gt;, and the completion of &lt;a href=&quot;https://frankmcpherson.blog/2024/11/30/finished-reading-the.html&quot;&gt;another book&lt;/a&gt;. I also packed up and shipped out the Pixel Watch and Macbook Air." created="Mon, 02 Dec 2024 14:29:52 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			</outline>
		</body>
	</opml>
