<?xml version="1.0"?>
<opml version="2.0">
	<head>
		<title>2024-06</title>
		<dateCreated>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 13:14:35 GMT</dateCreated>
		<dateModified>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 13:15:16 GMT</dateModified>
		<ownerId>frank.mcpherson@gmail.com</ownerId>
		<urlUpdateSocket>wss://drummer.land/</urlUpdateSocket>
		<ownerName>Frank McPherson</ownerName>
		<ownerEmail>frank.mcpherson@gmail.com</ownerEmail>
		<expansionState>1,2,5,9,10,19,21,22,29</expansionState>
		<lastCursor>1</lastCursor>
		</head>
	<body>
		<outline text="June 2024" created="Sat, 01 Jun 2024 21:27:51 GMT" name="june2024" type="calendarMonth">
			<outline text="" created="Wed, 26 Jun 2024 20:55:39 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="26">
				<outline text="I have a negative reflexive reaction to AI &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jetbrains.com/grazie/&quot;&gt;writing generation tools&lt;/a&gt;, probably mostly because I like to write and I can't imagine why I would want an AI to write for me. On the other hand, having worked in IT my entire life I know that the lack of good documentation is one of the weakest links of IT. Sure, some documentation is written but then is never maintained nor often never read. These are reasons why I think documentation as code and software defined infrastructure are so valuable." created="Wed, 26 Jun 2024 21:18:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Is it because I have no interest in it, or is that the Apple Vision Pro is losing steam?" created="Wed, 26 Jun 2024 20:55:40 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 13" created="Thu, 13 Jun 2024 14:35:00 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="13">
				<outline text="Reading about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imore.com/mac/macos/macos-sequoia-review-hands-on&quot;&gt;the updates in Mac OS  Sequoia.&lt;/a&gt; What I find most irritable with OS X that when I connect my Macbook Air to my dock and external monitor the dock does not appear at the bottom of the monitor screen. I don't have my Macbook side by side with the monitor, but rather below so the external monitor is above the internal monitor and it seems OS X really doesn't know what to do about that.   " created="Thu, 13 Jun 2024 20:06:42 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Here is &lt;a href=&quot;https://interconnected.org/more/2024/06/Apple-Intelligence-architecture.jpg&quot;&gt;a drawing of the Apple Intelligence architecture&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Thu, 13 Jun 2024 15:52:32 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="The main reason why I have invested in and use Google's hardware, mostly phones running Android, all these years is that I believe the idea of &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search/howsearchworks/our-approach/&quot;&gt;organizing the world's information&lt;/a&gt;&quot; best aligns to how I think about personal computing. Years ago I wrote about these ideas and how I saw the &lt;a href=&quot;https://realpersonalcomputing.com/2011/12/26/post-pc-era-or-the-beginning-of-the-personal-computing-era/&quot;&gt;emergence of smartphones and tablets as the true, real, personal computing moment&lt;/a&gt;. I &lt;a href=&quot;https://realpersonalcomputing.com/2011/12/31/lets-get-real/&quot;&gt;defined personal computing&lt;/a&gt; as hardware + software (apps) + Internet + intelligence and believed then that Google was closest to meeting this definition with what was emerging as Google Assistant. I think now that Apple's description and implementation of Apple Intelligence is closer to actualizing what I imagined back then. " created="Thu, 13 Jun 2024 14:35:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 12" created="Wed, 12 Jun 2024 13:20:32 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="12">
				<outline text="A People's AI" created="Wed, 12 Jun 2024 13:30:16 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Over the last year we've seen Microsoft, Google, and now Apple demonstrate what they are doing with AI.  As a somewhat casual observer, it seems to me all of these announcements fall in what I will call a &quot;me too&quot; category. Microsoft added a ChatGPT bot to Bing so Google had to add Gemini chat to Search. Microsoft added AI features to Office and Google did the same to Gmail and Docs. The problem with this matching of functionality is that both companies are focused on each other rather than their customers." created="Wed, 12 Jun 2024 13:31:10 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The main challenges to broad use of the latest AI tools is how easy they are to use and explaining what specifically they do and why a person should want to use them. So far the most publicized uses are enhanced search, writing, and creating pictures. In a way not unlike&lt;a href=&quot;https://newtonglossary.com/terms/egg-freckles&quot;&gt; how the handwriting recognition of the Apple Newton Messagepad was treated&lt;/a&gt;, there is more attention put on how these AI tools are doing things wrong and often times with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/23/24162896/google-ai-overview-hallucinations-glue-in-pizza&quot;&gt;hilarious results&lt;/a&gt;. Personally, my use of GPTs has been as an enhanced search, and I prefer to do my own writing. " created="Wed, 12 Jun 2024 13:20:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="How Microsoft and Google have handled AI as response to each other is not surprising because honestly that is how these companies operate as they are competing against each other for corporate customers. Microsoft and Google both have retail consumer products but these are layers on top of a corporate DNA, and frankly it shows. Apple's DNA has consumers woven from top to bottom and we see and feel this in their actual products and how they talk about them, and frankly that makes them more relatable and trustworthy to consumers." created="Wed, 12 Jun 2024 13:47:50 GMT"/>
					<outline text="While I find it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/hokey&quot;&gt;hokey&lt;/a&gt;, the &quot;branding&quot; of these features as &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=apple+intelligence&amp;oq=apple+intelligenc&amp;gs_lcrp=EgZjaHJvbWUqDQgAEAAYgwEYsQMYgAQyDQgAEAAYgwEYsQMYgAQyBggBEAAYAzIGCAIQRRg5MgYIAxAAGAMyBggEEAAYAzIGCAUQRRg9MgYIBhBFGD0yBggHEEUYPagCALACAA&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8&quot;&gt;Apple Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&quot; is consistent with Apple's opinionated approach to all technology. Apple's message is clear, they are not going to use AI in the same way as others, so much so that they call it something similar to but not the same was what others call it. Apple is saying AI is not Artificial Intelligence, it's Apple Intelligence. " created="Wed, 12 Jun 2024 13:52:49 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Of course, Apple is doing the same thing as Microsoft and Google in adding AI features to their first party products, but there is a key differentiation between Apple and these others,  Apple is a hardware company and AI might be the biggest gift to Apple's long term prospects since the mobile phone. The biggest question at Microsoft and Google right now is, how can they make money from AI, and it turns out that for them the AI revenue flow looks the same as advertising and search, but that is not how AI generates revenue." created="Wed, 12 Jun 2024 13:58:00 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The hottest company on the planet right now is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=nvidia+stock&amp;sca_esv=0517884da1645327&amp;sxsrf=ADLYWIKECtPygZrsH04UhSYHetVbbMNadg%3A1718287573981&amp;ei=1fxqZuPCO_yvptQPk_Ov4AI&amp;oq=nvidia&amp;gs_lp=Egxnd3Mtd2l6LXNlcnAiBm52aWRpYSoCCAAyFRAAGIAEGLEDGEMYgwEYigUYRhj6ATIWEC4YgAQYsQMY0QMYQxiDARjHARiKBTIQEAAYgAQYsQMYQxiDARiKBTIKEAAYgAQYQxiKBTILEAAYgAQYsQMYgwEyCBAAGIAEGLEDMgsQABiABBixAxiDATILEAAYgAQYsQMYgwEyDhAAGIAEGLEDGIMBGIoFMgsQABiABBixAxiDATIhEAAYgAQYsQMYQxiDARiKBRhGGPoBGJcFGIwFGN0E2AEBSKwkUABYhwpwAHgBkAEAmAFtoAGfBKoBAzUuMbgBAcgBAPgBAZgCBqAC4ATCAgQQIxgnwgILEC4YgAQYsQMYgwHCAhEQLhiABBixAxjRAxiDARjHAcICERAAGIAEGJECGLEDGIMBGIoFwgIFEAAYgASYAwC6BgYIARABGBOSBwM0LjKgB-w7&amp;sclient=gws-wiz-serp&quot;&gt;Nvidia&lt;/a&gt;, who manufacture the processing chips (GPUs) AI needs to quickly provide results. Ever since Apple announced they put their M1 processors in iPads and similar high end processors in the iPhone, there have been questions about why Apple is putting all this processing horse power in these products when it will never be fully used. The answer to that question should be obvious now, that processing power is needed to run these new AI tools with performance similar to Nvidia. People expect Apple to keep their data on their iPhones, iPads, and Macs and their processors allow them to do that. " created="Wed, 12 Jun 2024 14:02:41 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I own the Macbook Air that has Apple's first M-series processor, and its going to be three years old in November.  The Macbook Air M1 does everything I normally do, web browsing, checking email, some writing, crunching numbers, so fast I can't imagine when I will need to replace it for these purposes. Last week I installed &lt;a href=&quot;https://ollama.ai&quot;&gt;Ollama&lt;/a&gt; on this Macbook Air so that I can run AI models like &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.meta.com/blog/meta-llama-3/&quot;&gt;llama3&lt;/a&gt; locally and for the first time since I've owned it the Macbook was slow! Before this I imagined the reason why I would replace this Macbook Air is that Apple no longer supported it in the latest release of OS X, which could be ten years from now, but now I know that if I want to run future models locally I will want a newer Macbook. " created="Wed, 12 Jun 2024 14:08:41 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Cloud-based AI has it's place in providing widely available information in a comprehensible manner, but when it comes to actually doing things for people, that AI processing will need to be on the edge and near the people. The people behind &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rabbit.tech/newsroom/introducing-r1&quot;&gt;the Rabbit R1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://humane.com/aipin&quot;&gt;the Humane AI Pin&lt;/a&gt; recognize this, but both are physically small and thus constrained. The perfect AI edge device is the smartphone, and so AI fits &quot;glove-in-hand&quot; with Apple's core consumer product, while neither Microsoft or Google have such product. For Apple AI is not the &quot;thing&quot; and it will never be the &quot;thing,&quot; their &quot;thing&quot; is Apple silicon put in iPhones, iPads, and Macs, and AI makes the best case for the need of that &quot;thing&quot; than anything that has come before. " created="Wed, 12 Jun 2024 14:17:31 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 10" created="Mon, 10 Jun 2024 17:36:42 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="10">
				<outline text="I started an outline of my notes about the Apple WWDC keynote here but moved them to &lt;a href=&quot;http://pagepark.frankmcpherson.net/2024WWDC.opml&quot;&gt;their own outline file&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 10 Jun 2024 20:06:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 6" created="Thu, 06 Jun 2024 13:56:27 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="06">
				<outline text="Google Updates NotebookLM" created="Thu, 06 Jun 2024 14:33:55 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Google has released &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/6/24172422/google-notebooklm-ai-gemini-pro-chatbot&quot;&gt;an update to NotebookLM&lt;/a&gt; that allows one to provide specific sources to Google's Gemini LLM, store the results from questions about those sources, and write and store your own notes. I first learned about NotebookLM from Steven Johnson who consulted Google in it's development of this product. &lt;a href=&quot;https://stevenberlinjohnson.com/my-books-bf38f309b6d7&quot;&gt;Johnson is the author of several books&lt;/a&gt; such as &quot;How We Got To Now: Six Innovations That Made the Modern World&quot; and has used DEVONThink for is research and writing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://stevenberlinjohnson.com/how-to-use-notebooklm-as-a-research-tool-6ad5c3a227cc&quot;&gt;Johnson describes NotebookLM&lt;/a&gt; as the type of tool he would find useful in &lt;a href=&quot;https://adjacentpossible.substack.com/p/designing-a-workflow-for-thinking&quot;&gt;his research and writing&lt;/a&gt;, suggesting that NotebookLM is intended to fill scholarly and writing type use cases. " created="Thu, 06 Jun 2024 13:56:28 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="I am following the development of and trying out NotebookLM because the use cases Johnson describes align with my interests. Right now Google is focusing on input of content and there are no formal methods for producing output beyond copy and paste. I assume at some point in time Google will allow creation of documents in Google Docs." created="Thu, 06 Jun 2024 15:04:18 GMT"/>
					<outline text="Prior releases of NotebookLM allowed me to upload a small number of PDFs or Google Docs from Google Drive as sources, and the new update allows me to specify web sites. It does not crawl an entire domain, it appears to GET the HTML page for the URL you provide. I have found that &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2019/06/02/150411.html&quot;&gt;Dave Winer's Old School CMS&lt;/a&gt; that publishes my Daynotes structures the writing in a way that works well with NotebookLM." created="Thu, 06 Jun 2024 14:37:26 GMT"/>
					<outline text="As you can see from my &lt;a href=&quot;http://pagepark.frankmcpherson.net/archive.opml&quot;&gt;Monthly Index&lt;/a&gt;, Old School creates a page for each month of the year for all of the posts published in that month, for example here is &lt;a href=&quot;http://oldschool.scripting.com/frank.mcpherson@gmail.com/2024/02/&quot;&gt;all of the blog posts I wrote here in May, 2024.&lt;/a&gt; To have NotebookLM use my Daynotes as the source for answers all I have to do is provide it the URL for each of the of the monthly pages. I am surprised that so far I haven't reached a limit to the number of web site URLs I can provide as sources because there is a limit in how many files (PDFs or Google Docs) one can provide." created="Thu, 06 Jun 2024 14:41:18 GMT"/>
					<outline text="I have entered all of the monthly URLs for 2021 through May, 2024 and then asked it to summarize what I wrote about in each year. You can save responses to the notebook, but sources are not included in what is saved, although you can get to them from the chat. When you click a source link from chat a pane opens with the source content that you can highlight and then save verbatim to the notebook or have Gemini summarize the highlighted content and save the summarization to a note." created="Thu, 06 Jun 2024 14:50:04 GMT"/>
					<outline text="One can copy and paste the content of a note, and I did that with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://pagepark.frankmcpherson.net/2022Summary.opml&quot;&gt;2022 Summary of my daynotes&lt;/a&gt;, pasting it in to Drummer. I lightly edited the result in Drummer for formatting. My recommendation to Google would be to create the notes in markdown so that formatting will also carry over. " created="Thu, 06 Jun 2024 18:01:53 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 1" created="Sat, 01 Jun 2024 21:27:52 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="01">
				<outline text="I bought the Macbook Air M1 back in November, 2021, and from that time up until today I had never run anything on it that impacted performance. Today I installed &lt;a href=&quot;https://ollama.com/&quot;&gt;Ollama&lt;/a&gt; and and tried the llama2 model and found saw the CPU utilization jump up to nearly 70% and the YouTube video I was watching disrupted. Basically, when interacting with llama2 I cannnot really run something else on the Mac. " created="Sat, 01 Jun 2024 21:27:53 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			</outline>
		</body>
	</opml>
