<?xml version="1.0"?>
<opml version="2.0">
	<head>
		<title>2025-04</title>
		<dateCreated>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 17:15:02 GMT</dateCreated>
		<dateModified>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 17:15:40 GMT</dateModified>
		<ownerId>frank.mcpherson@gmail.com</ownerId>
		<urlUpdateSocket>wss://drummer.land/</urlUpdateSocket>
		<ownerName>Frank McPherson</ownerName>
		<ownerEmail>frank.mcpherson@gmail.com</ownerEmail>
		<expansionState>1</expansionState>
		<lastCursor>0</lastCursor>
		</head>
	<body>
		<outline text="April 2025" created="Wed, 02 Apr 2025 17:14:12 GMT" name="april2025" type="calendarMonth">
			<outline text="April 30" created="Wed, 30 Apr 2025 13:26:39 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="30">
				<outline text="I think that one thing that can explain much about the United States right now is unresolved corporate trauma that has built up over years and manifests in fear, distrust, and anger with the government. The trauma started with the assignations of John F Kennedy, Robert Kennedy, and Martin Luther King Jr, spread significantly by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2025/apr/30/vietnam-war-documentary-netflix&quot;&gt;the war in Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;, the war on drugs in the United States and to date culminated on 9/11 it's on follow wars. Gen X and subsequent generations grew up in the stew of these traumas while the Baby Boomers were the first affected and the first to react. You could say there is a line between those taking advantage of the trauma and those trapped by the trauma. " created="Wed, 30 Apr 2025 18:49:32 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Looks like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dhs.gov/real-id/real-id-faqs&quot;&gt;Real ID is not proof of citizenship&lt;/a&gt; nor is a drivers license. Do you carry a passport with you everywhere? " created="Wed, 30 Apr 2025 13:26:40 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 29" created="Tue, 29 Apr 2025 15:25:32 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="29">
				<outline text="Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/comcasts-customers-dropping-like-flies-just-like-verizons/&quot;&gt;this report saying that Comcast is losing TV and broadband customers &lt;/a&gt;and I am not surprised. I am both a TV and broadband customer but don't think Comcast is doing much to keep my business. One way they could do that is by dropping their broadband data cap or at the very least increase it by 2x. We learned during Covid that there really is not a cost impact to Comcast from increased consumer downloads." created="Tue, 29 Apr 2025 19:11:54 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I need to improve my ability to monitor network traffic on my home network, particularly traffic going out/coming in from the Internet because I seem be bumping up against Xfinity's bandwidth cap. We went over this month and I think that was due to some sync with Onedrive that went wrong with a couple of my virtual machines. " created="Tue, 29 Apr 2025 15:25:33 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 28" created="Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:13:11 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="28">
				<outline text="By most reports the Chicago Cubs wrapped up their toughest two weeks of the schedule &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleedcubbieblue.com/2025/4/28/24419488/2025-cubs-heroes-and-goats-game-29&quot;&gt;last night&lt;/a&gt; and enter the first series against divisional opponent Pittsburgh with a 17-12 overall record and a 1.5 game lead in the N.L. Central. In short, they exceeded expectations. However, for me, the upcoming month against lesser opponents will be more telling. Will the Cubs play down to their competition, which has been a problem in the past, and end May with just a few games above .500 or will they extend their overall record to well above .500 by dominating the lesser opponents? Good teams beat the teams they are supposed to beat, and they are supposed to beat Pittsburgh so I am looking for a sweep or at least win the first two for a chance to sweep." created="Mon, 28 Apr 2025 17:29:03 GMT" type="outline" image="https://shared.frankmcpherson.net/images/small/cubsPlayoffCount.jpg"/>
				<outline text="Submitted my blog to &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogroll.org&quot;&gt;blogroll.org&lt;/a&gt;" created="Mon, 28 Apr 2025 15:29:53 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2025/04/27.html#a155941&quot;&gt;Polls of public opinion&lt;/a&gt; matter to people who hold office if they believe that the public can and will remove them from office. Trump and the people directing his administration are not acting as though the fear they can lose their office. Given they are obvious in their disregard for the Constitution I expect some justification will come to delay or cancel elections, or the rules will be such that only their supporters can vote." created="Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:13:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 24" created="Thu, 24 Apr 2025 15:06:06 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="24">
				<outline text="I have done more experimentation with &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordland.social&quot;&gt;Wordland&lt;/a&gt; today. The template that I am using on &lt;a href=&quot;https://fjmnotes.com/&quot;&gt;my Wordpress site&lt;/a&gt; requires titles for posts because it uses the title as the link to the post. The top page is only an index to posts and doesn't display of the post content. One can make the template use the date as a link to the post. I am surprised that Wordland requires publshing posts to Wordpress before adding to &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordland.social/fjmnotes/3644780/rss.xml&quot;&gt;the RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;, it would seem to me that publishing to Wordpress would be optional but that by default everything that one saves is added to the RSS feed. I would expect Wordland to first and foremost be a simple way to build and maintain a RSS feed apart from publishing to any destination because that would provide for the ultimate flexibility. It could even be used apart from Wordpress.  In short, unless I change the template &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2025/04/24.html#a135855&quot;&gt;writing posts without titles in Wordland&lt;/a&gt; is pointless to me." created="Thu, 24 Apr 2025 15:06:07 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 21" created="Mon, 21 Apr 2025 15:04:29 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="21">
				<outline text="I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://readwise.io/reader/shared/01jscnz37kd0dhq76a8556rwpn&quot;&gt;this post about the desktop computing metaphor&lt;/a&gt; and when I read the description of an itemized operating system my experience with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newton_OS&quot;&gt;NewtonOS&lt;/a&gt; immediately came to mind. What I remember is that everything in NewtonOS was an object and data was separate from objects so that you didn't need duplicate data. I am probably not doing the topic justice, but I do believe NewtonOS was the only &quot;object oriented&quot; operating system that I have ever personally used. Regardless, I really would like what is being described in the post because I agree that the desktop and window metaphor is no longer the best way for us to do personal computing." created="Mon, 21 Apr 2025 21:26:20 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Today &lt;a href=&quot;https://dfarq.homeip.net/timex-sinclair-1000&quot;&gt;Dave Farquhar wrote&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&quot;https://frankmcpherson.blog/2021/09/17/sir-sinclair-and.html&quot;&gt;the first computer I personally ever owned&lt;/a&gt;, the Timex Sinclair 1000. Dave includes a link to &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.bradgrier.com/2022/12/15/ts1000-upgrade-log-entry-1/&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; written by a guy who is reviving and upgrading a TS 1000.  For a glimpse of what it was like to use this computer, look at the second to last picture on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.bradgrier.com/2023/03/14/ts1000-upgrade-log-entry-4-oh-the-memories-well-make-with-16k/&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; that shows the display of a game called Dungeon Crawling. One of the&quot;official&quot; games that one could buy was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crazygames.com/game/frogger&quot;&gt;Frogger&lt;/a&gt;, which my buddy Ray renamed Wood Tick once he saw how huge the flattened frog became when &quot;hit' by an object. This post triggered the selection of &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.crucialtracks.org/profile/frankm/20250421&quot;&gt;my Crucial Track for today&lt;/a&gt;." created="Mon, 21 Apr 2025 15:04:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 17" created="Thu, 17 Apr 2025 18:05:40 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="17">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://endonend.org/about/&quot;&gt;Jason&lt;/a&gt; has &lt;a href=&quot;https://endonend.org/2025/04/17/crucial-tracks-the-app-the.html&quot;&gt;released&lt;/a&gt; his app, Crucial Tracks, which is a web app for journaling about music. The app is an add-on to his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crucialtracks.org/&quot;&gt;Crucial Tracks blog&lt;/a&gt;. I have signed up to create my own &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.crucialtracks.org/profile/frankm&quot;&gt;profile&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.crucialtracks.org/profile/frankm/feed&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; that you can subscribe to, or see my entries on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.blog/frankm&quot;&gt;micro.blog&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/frankm.bsky.social&quot;&gt;Bluesky&lt;/a&gt; profiles." created="Thu, 17 Apr 2025 18:05:41 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&gt;If citizens endorse the idea that people named by authorities as &quot;criminals&quot; or &quot;terrorists&quot; have no right to due process, then they are accepting that they themselves have no right to due process. It is due process, and due process alone, that allows you to demonstrate that you are a citizen. Without it, the masked men in the black vans can simply claim that you are a foreign terrorist and disappear you.  -- &lt;a href=&quot;https://snyder.substack.com/p/state-terror&quot;&gt;Tim Snyder&lt;/a&gt;" created="Thu, 17 Apr 2025 20:31:04 GMT" type="markdown"/>
				<outline text="Another way to say the above is, innocent until proven guilty. It is the obligation of the state to prove a person's guilt, not the obligation of a person to prove their innocence, and this applies to citizens and non-citizens." created="Thu, 17 Apr 2025 20:33:20 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 14" created="Mon, 14 Apr 2025 13:58:15 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="14">
				<outline text="Inbound RSS" created="Mon, 14 Apr 2025 15:11:57 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="Dave &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2025/04/14/121946.html&quot;&gt;elaborates&lt;/a&gt; on what he means by inbound RSS. In my experience micro.blog is the only site that enables this in a couple of different ways. You can either have items from inbound RSS feeds appear in your timeline or to import posts from a feed to your blog. The import is intended to be a one time activity and not something that happens in an ongoing manner, so it doesn't meet Dave's use case." created="Mon, 14 Apr 2025 13:58:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="In a roundabout way I have been using inbound RSS for some time by using &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com/&quot;&gt;If This Then That&lt;/a&gt;. Posts that I publish to &lt;a href=&quot;https://frankmcpherson.blog/&quot;&gt;my main blog&lt;/a&gt; get cross-posted to &lt;a href=&quot;https://fjmnotes.com/&quot;&gt;a Wordpress site&lt;/a&gt;, which I &lt;a href=&quot;https://fjmnotes.com/2008/05/10/welcome-to-my-new-site/&quot;&gt;created back in 2008&lt;/a&gt; as a replacement to the blog I first created using EditThisPage. The IFTTT applet monitors the RSS feed of my blog and when it finds a new entry it posts that to my Wordpress site. " created="Mon, 14 Apr 2025 15:01:06 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://fjmnotes.com/2025/04/14/frank-blogged-on-april-14-2025-at-0903am-2/&quot;&gt;Here is an example&lt;/a&gt;. At the bottom of the post you see the source citation, &quot;from Routine Revelations&quot; along with the link to the source.  A problem I had when I set this up is that Wordpress requires titles for all blog posts whereas my main blog doesn't require titles, such as was the case with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://frankmcpherson.blog/2025/04/14/good-news-the-chicago-cubs.html&quot;&gt;source post&lt;/a&gt; to above example. The work around is to automatically create a title using the date and time as a unique identifier." created="Mon, 14 Apr 2025 15:13:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="When I first started using IFTTT I had applets monitoring my Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram accounts and also cross posting this to the Wordpress site. My idea is that the site would be &lt;a href=&quot;https://fjmnotes.com/archive/&quot;&gt;an archive of all of my posts&lt;/a&gt; across all these sites. &lt;a href=&quot;https://fjmnotes.com/2015/07/31/once-in-a-blue-moon-is-so-rare-that-even-when-there-is-supposed-to-be-a-blue-moon-there-isnt/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is an example from Facebook. and &lt;a href=&quot;https://fjmnotes.com/2020/10/23/frank-tweeted-on-october-23-2020-at-1056am/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is an example from Twitter. If you look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://fjmnotes.com/2020/09/&quot;&gt;the archive page from September 2020&lt;/a&gt; you see a mix of blog posts and tweets and you even see some articles I favorited and shared from Pocket. Over time the social media accounts disabled the API that IFTTT to block this functionality and thus I lost this functionality. Now that Bluesky provides outbound RSS I could set up IFTTT monitoring of it but in practice I only cross post to Bluesky from my main blog, so monitoring Bluesky would be redundant.  " created="Mon, 14 Apr 2025 15:14:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="My point is that a practical use case for inbound &lt;b&gt;and&lt;/b&gt; outbound RSS is the consolidation and archival of one's Internet posts across multiple source locations." created="Mon, 14 Apr 2025 15:26:29 GMT" type="outline"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 11" created="Fri, 11 Apr 2025 13:12:16 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="11">
				<outline text="When we are left to having to scrape up a few micro controllers to cobble together a computer, there will be &lt;a href=&quot;https://collapseos.org/why.html&quot;&gt;Collapse OS&lt;/a&gt;. " created="Fri, 11 Apr 2025 13:12:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 10" created="Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:02:50 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="10">
				<outline text="Today is Pixel 9a day, I see a number of reviews that have been posted and I received an email from Google telling me I can go purchase my own. " created="Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:02:51 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Early Results" created="Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:18:28 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="A MLB team cannot win their division in April, but they can lose it. Going in to the middle of April we are seeing positive results from the Chicago Cubs, although they  suffered the first set back of the season when Justin Steele was put on the 15 day IL. Right now they are at the top of the NL Central with a half game lead but that doesn't matter as much as the +28 run differential that is the best in the league. The runs they scored during this last home stand in cold April weather is a very positive sign." created="Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:18:42 GMT"/>
					<outline text="On Friday the Cubs start a 6 game road trip in Los Angeles and then San Diego, and I think these games are a good early test for the Cubs. I want to see them win at least two games in LA and win one in San Diego. The Dodgers have actually fallen back to earth going 6-4 over the last ten while the Padres has jumped up to the top of the NL West over the Dodgers and Giants. I will feel good about a split on this road trip. " created="Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:22:13 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 7" created="Mon, 07 Apr 2025 16:56:24 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="07">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hamiltonnolan.com/p/divergence-from-the-interests-of&quot;&gt;Why is Trumping do this&lt;/a&gt;?" created="Mon, 07 Apr 2025 21:32:45 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&gt;The most honest explanation for Trump’s actions are: He is insane. He suffers from a number of pathologies. That is fairly clear. The more important question is: &lt;b&gt;How has this insane man managed to gain control of the government of the world’s richest and most powerful nation? That, my friends, is the unfortunate outcome of an economic system that has so profoundly failed to enforce economic equality, and a political system that so profoundly failed to protect its democracy from the influence of capital that it allowed itself to be totally captured by extreme lunatics backed by extreme wealth.&lt;/b&gt; And here we are. The whole thing is most notable for its absurdity. If it’s any consolation, all the capitalists who led us down this road are going to lose a shitload of money. Ha ha, fuckers." created="Mon, 07 Apr 2025 21:32:59 GMT" type="markdown"/>
				<outline text="The Purpose Of Government" created="Mon, 07 Apr 2025 17:04:45 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://intellectualoid.com/2025/04/06/monday-april-7-a-tad-early/&quot;&gt;Without due process&lt;/a&gt;, a claim of guilt is simply one man's word over another. Without due process we are simply being asked to believe the claims that the humans they labeled as terrorists and thus deserving of deportation and imprisonment are in fact deserving of that label and loss of liberty. Due process is how governments insure that the right to liberty endowed by our creator is preserved. " created="Mon, 07 Apr 2025 16:56:25 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="&gt;We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights, that among these are Life, Liberty and the pursuit of Happiness.--That to secure these rights, Governments are instituted among Men, deriving their just powers from the consent of the governed. -- Thomas Jefferson, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archives.gov/founding-docs/declaration-transcript&quot;&gt;The Declaration of Independence&lt;/a&gt;" created="Mon, 07 Apr 2025 17:02:06 GMT" type="markdown"/>
					<outline text="The Declaration Of Independence is important because it defines the values of the United States of America. It says the rights of life, liberty, and pursuit of happiness is not only secured for citizens but for all people because we all have the same creator. Due process for everyone is how we live out our values in the United States and denying that to anyone makes us hypocrites at best." created="Mon, 07 Apr 2025 17:06:17 GMT" type="outline"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 5" created="Sat, 05 Apr 2025 16:18:48 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="05">
				<outline text="One of the reasons why I bought the Macbook Pro last fall is that I anticipated prices will increase with Trump entering office. I sold some of stock to make the purchase, and I now realize that was a second good reason for the timing as that pool of stock has less value today. Thanks Trump!" created="Sat, 05 Apr 2025 16:23:20 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I am wondering today about the price of things that I eat every day, blueberries, yogurt, bread, and my fondness for guacamole. I've seen was the tariffs are doing to my retirement savings, but I have yet to see it impact my daily life, but that will happen soon!  Thanks Trump!" created="Sat, 05 Apr 2025 16:18:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 3" created="Thu, 03 Apr 2025 18:11:21 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="03">
				<outline text="Annotating PDFs Versus Using Notebooks On Boox Tablets" created="Thu, 03 Apr 2025 19:24:02 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I am using a Boox Note Air 3C as my primary notetaking tablet and I am using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mydeepguide.com/shop&quot;&gt;a daily organizer PDF&lt;/a&gt;. For the past year I have been using an app called NeoReader to open the PDF that I then annotate with my handwriting, and that has worked very well. However, a shortcoming of annotating a PDF on this device is that I cannot search for that handwriting, to find something I basically have to recall the date on which I  wrote something and go to that page. The cool thing about the PDF is that it's a very robust template and includes hyperlinks to move throughout the file, which makes it function more like an app than a document." created="Thu, 03 Apr 2025 18:11:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="The latest version of the Boox firmware for the Note Air 3C adds the ability to create notebooks using a PDF as a template. After upgrading my Note Air 3C to this version of the firmware I created a new notebook using the daily organizer PDF and I found that the linking function exists in the notebook. The benefit of using a notebook is that I can search for handwriting, which makes it much easier to find something. Prior to using the Note Air 3C I had been using OneNote on an iPad that also supports search of handwriting, so I have missed this feature." created="Thu, 03 Apr 2025 18:21:31 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="Boox notebooks are backed up to PDF files that I have configured to sync with my OneDrive account and I also use SyncThing to sync copies to file shares on computers on my home network. The problem is, the links are not preserved in the backup files, which are an export of the notebook, so navigation through the backup files is not as easy as with the annotated versions of the PDF that I had been using. I also cannot  search for handwriting in the backup files." created="Thu, 03 Apr 2025 19:04:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="If I had a way to perform a type of OCR indexing of the annotated PDFs so that I could do searches on a PC I probably would stick with that approach, using NeoReader, rather than using the original PDF as a template for a notebook. " created="Thu, 03 Apr 2025 19:07:12 GMT" type="outline"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="April 2" created="Wed, 02 Apr 2025 17:14:13 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="02">
				<outline text="It is a cold and damp day here in southeast Michigan, which has me wishing to be back in Phoenix watching the Cubs during spring training." created="Wed, 02 Apr 2025 18:38:49 GMT" type="outline" image="https://shared.frankmcpherson.net/images/small/springTraining2025Small.jpg"/>
				<outline text="While the header graphic is not what I normally think of as spring, I did take it in spring while in Phoenix, and I might keep that one there all summer!" created="Wed, 02 Apr 2025 17:56:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Happy April 2! I need to get the top graphic on this page changed over to something not winter. " created="Wed, 02 Apr 2025 17:14:14 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Mesa, Arizona, March 2025" created="Wed, 02 Apr 2025 18:36:33 GMT" inlineImage="https://shared.frankmcpherson.net/images/phoenixPalmTrees.jpg"/>
				</outline>
			</outline>
		</body>
	</opml>
