<?xml version="1.0"?>
<opml version="2.0">
	<head>
		<title>2025-06</title>
		<dateCreated>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 13:12:58 GMT</dateCreated>
		<dateModified>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 13:13:26 GMT</dateModified>
		<ownerId>frank.mcpherson@gmail.com</ownerId>
		<urlUpdateSocket>wss://drummer.land/</urlUpdateSocket>
		<ownerName>Frank McPherson</ownerName>
		<ownerEmail>frank.mcpherson@gmail.com</ownerEmail>
		<expansionState>1</expansionState>
		<lastCursor>2</lastCursor>
		</head>
	<body>
		<outline text="June 2025" created="Mon, 02 Jun 2025 17:10:44 GMT" name="june2025" type="calendarMonth">
			<outline text="June 30" created="Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:45:48 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="30">
				<outline text="For some reason left-click on a link using Chrome on Linux has become difficult. Seems I have to find just the right spot to get the context menu to appear, other times it opens and closes really fast." created="Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:45:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="We The People" created="Mon, 30 Jun 2025 15:41:45 GMT" type="markdown">
					<outline text="Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://readwise.io/reader/shared/01jz0n3ktyvdj67banq1y2fxkn&quot;&gt;this really good article about Bill Moyers&lt;/a&gt; upon the occurrence if his passing. Those of us unwilling to close our eyes to what is happening in the United States know why it is happening, it's because the hierarchical/supremacy basis of the norm of civilization demands exclusivity over inclusion. In other words from the founding citizens of the United States have been in a struggle over the definition of &quot;We The People.&quot;    " created="Mon, 30 Jun 2025 15:41:58 GMT"/>
					<outline text="The article tells the story of Moyers' first act of journalism, a series of stories about a group of women in Texas who argued that Social Security was unconstitutional. The key point is this made by Moyers upon reflection about the women in his reporting." created="Mon, 30 Jun 2025 15:47:40 GMT"/>
					<outline text="&gt;“It came to me one day many years later,” he continued. “Fiercely loyal to their families, to their clubs, charities and congregations — fiercely loyal, in other words, to their own kind — they narrowly defined democracy to include only people like themselves.” Many of their own neighbors, he realized, were, to these Social Security skeptics, not as much a part of the democracy as they were. “We the people,” narrowly defined." created="Mon, 30 Jun 2025 15:49:57 GMT"/>
					<outline text="All aspects of society, including Christianity, is driven by exclusivity and its sibling, scarcity. Christianity in particular has failed us because its associated institutions were best positioned to prevent what is happening had they actually taught the theology of Jesus rather than of empire, to practice inclusion and thus be the light for the nations that the Jewish prophets said was Israel's calling. Christianity failed when it was tempted, providing evidence of its disconnect from the body of Christ.  " created="Mon, 30 Jun 2025 15:53:49 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 28" created="Sat, 28 Jun 2025 18:31:35 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="28">
				<outline text="Following up on the new Xfinity plans announced a few days ago, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/stung-by-customer-losses-comcast-says-all-its-new-plans-have-unlimited-data/&quot;&gt;this Ars article&lt;/a&gt; says that customers won't automatically get unlimited data but can &quot;repackage&quot; in to one in which then can. So far I do not see an option to move to a plan that is not higher bandwidth, and thus cost, than my current plan. I do not want to pay more per month, I just want to get rid of the data cap. The most ironic thing is later in the article there is a quote from Comcast executives regarding why they are losing customers and they state as reasons &quot;One is price transparency and predictability and the other is the level of ease of doing business with us.&quot; The later is most definitely an issue when they do not provide an easy way to talk with a human being, instead every online interaction is directed to a chatbot that does not provide answers. If Comcast really wants to make it easy to do business with them they ought to prioritize enabling their customers to simply make changes via their portal. Better yet, why not just drop caps from all users automatically rather than make your customers jump through hoops? " created="Sat, 28 Jun 2025 18:31:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 26" created="Thu, 26 Jun 2025 19:08:55 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="26">
				<outline text="I hope this isn't a tease. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/693762/comcast-xfinity-internet-plans-unlimited-data-caps&quot;&gt;The Verge&lt;/a&gt; says &lt;a href=&quot;https://corporate.comcast.com/press/releases/comcast-new-national-xfinity-internet-packages-unlimited-data-advanced-wifi-gateway&quot;&gt;Xfinity is dropping their data caps&lt;/a&gt;. I am trying to find more information on the Xfinity web site but having trouble. I don't think there is a way to make the change at this point in time. My fear is that they are going to push me to the Internet WiFi gateway that has a monthly cost, right now I have my own modem and access point so I do not pay Xfinity for rent on any Internet connectivity. " created="Thu, 26 Jun 2025 19:08:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 25" created="Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:33:35 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="25">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.google/technology/developers/introducing-gemini-cli-open-source-ai-agent/&quot;&gt;Google has released&lt;/a&gt; a Linux terminal (CLI) agent for Gemini, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli&quot;&gt;Gemini CLI&lt;/a&gt;, that I have installed on my remote desktop container. One of the things I can with it is create thumbnail versions of image files like the one to the right. Gemini used &lt;a href=&quot;https://imagemagick.org/&quot;&gt;imagemagick&lt;/a&gt; to create the file using convert. First I listed the contents of the folder containing the original JPG then told it to create a thumbnail version of the Phoenix Palm Trees image, which is the same picture as the banner picture above. Another thing I tried is I asked Gemini to summarize the PDFs that are in my Downloads folder. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli/blob/main/docs/index.md&quot;&gt;Here is a link&lt;/a&gt; to the Gemini CLI documentation." created="Wed, 25 Jun 2025 15:05:30 GMT" type="outline" image="https://shared.frankmcpherson.net/images/small/phoenixPalmTreesSunset_thumbnail.jpg"/>
				<outline text="The wheels have fall off the Chicago Cubs pitching. Since last Thursday, June 19 Cubs pitchers have given up seven or more runs per game, six of which (not surprisingly) were losses. At this rate the Cubs will be out of first place in the NL Central by the end of next week. The big problem too many walks and too many home runs.  " created="Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:33:36 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 24" created="Tue, 24 Jun 2025 14:26:37 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="24">
				<outline text="I found this article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://readwise.io/reader/shared/01jy2zp6m90ydnajm0mkwap3rp&quot;&gt;The Fundamentalist Fallacy&lt;/a&gt;, yesterday and there is so much I am in agreement with that I almost highlighted the entire piece. I immediately purchased &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/War-Art-Steven-Pressfield-ebook/dp/B007A4SDCG&quot;&gt;The War of Art&lt;/a&gt;.   " created="Tue, 24 Jun 2025 14:26:38 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 23" created="Mon, 23 Jun 2025 14:42:48 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="23">
				<outline text="We are in the midst of a heat wave, three days or more in a row of 90 degree Fahrenheit temperatures and that makes me appreciate our new air conditioning. It also means there is a ten degree temperature difference between the top floor of our condo and the basement in which I work.  " created="Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:59:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Just read Martin Fowler's article on &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/articles/expert-generalist.html&quot;&gt;expert generalists&lt;/a&gt;&quot; and feel it defines me well, or at least how I aspire myself to be. In the IT services industry in which I work I don't think the contrast is specialists versus generalists but rather low cost labor versus high cost labor. My company has a focus on low cost labor, the consequence of  which I think is a decrease in curiosity and with it ownership or personal accountability. I mean people are conditioned to stay within their box because that is all they are being paid to do. I am convinced that what I see, and what I am describing, is a deliverable of a managerial culture within a company as opposed to a leadership culture." created="Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:17:21 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I am using both River5 and Feedland to monitor my RSS feeds. RSS items are retained longer in Feedland than in River5, so I use it to catch up on feeds over the last 24 hours or longer. River5 is where I go for the most recent stuff. Of course, I am also using Feedland to maintain my RSS subscriptions." created="Mon, 23 Jun 2025 15:17:53 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I really need to get a UPS for my home servers. As I rely more on my self hosted services I am more reliant on the servers being up. " created="Mon, 23 Jun 2025 15:08:34 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Imagine that you are indigenous to a land in which ever since outsiders discovered it, which starts at the time of Jesus, those outsiders treated you as sub-human and believed it was their right to take your land and kill your people. If you wrap your head around this you might understand a bit of what it must be like to live in the middle east. How anyone wonders why there are people in the middle east to hate us outsiders is beyond me. The only reason why we in the United States don't live in constant fear of those indigenous to this continent is because we outsiders, the immigrants, were more successful in our genocide. " created="Mon, 23 Jun 2025 14:50:01 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I completed the first of my twice a year trips around Lake Michigan to visit mom and friends. Drove 1,500 miles most of which in warmer than average temperatures. Enjoying our new air conditioning today!" created="Mon, 23 Jun 2025 14:42:49 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="All Enemies, Foreign and Domestic" created="Mon, 23 Jun 2025 16:01:19 GMT">
					<outline text="&gt;This outcome was something the Constitution was designed to prevent. &quot;The Framers of the Constitution were clear that only Congress is empowered to commence offensive military hostilities,&quot; former Rep. Justin Amash (L–Mich.) wrote on X. &quot;But there are people on the left and right who reject divided powers and fundamentally hate America. They're working deliberately and methodically to destroy it.&quot; " created="Mon, 23 Jun 2025 15:56:33 GMT" type="markdown"/>
					<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://reason.com/2025/06/21/trump-shreds-the-constitution-by-bombing-iran/&quot;&gt;Reason.com&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;Trump Shreds the Constitution By Bombing Iran&quot;" created="Mon, 23 Jun 2025 16:02:23 GMT"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 12" created="Thu, 12 Jun 2025 16:05:46 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="12">
				<outline text="Last year &lt;a href=&quot;https://frankmcpherson.blog/2024/06/12/on-this-date.html&quot;&gt;on this date&lt;/a&gt; the Chicago Cubs had a 32-35 record and would go on to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mlb.com/cubs/standings/2024&quot;&gt;83-79 record&lt;/a&gt; and finished 10 games behind Milwaukee in the NL Central. Right now they have a 41-27 record, are i&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mlb.com/cubs/standings/&quot;&gt;n first place in the NL Central &lt;/a&gt;and lead St. Louis by 5 games. The Cubs currently have the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mlb.com/cubs/standings/league&quot;&gt;second best record in the National League&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mlb.com/cubs/standings/mlb&quot;&gt;fourth best in the the MLB&lt;/a&gt;." created="Thu, 12 Jun 2025 16:05:47 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 11" created="Wed, 11 Jun 2025 15:02:29 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="11">
				<outline text="What you see today as the federal response to protests in the United States began with Richard Nixon's response to the Vietnam War protests which led to the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vera.org/reimagining-prison-webumentary/the-past-is-never-dead/drug-war-confessional&quot;&gt;war on drugs&lt;/a&gt;.&quot; Ronald Reagan continued that war on U.S. citizens and subverted Congress by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iran%E2%80%93Contra_affair&quot;&gt;illegally selling arms to Iran and diverting that money to the Contras&lt;/a&gt;. The executive branch power grew larger during George W. Bush's presidency in the immediate aftermath of 9/11 that brought &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patriot_Act&quot;&gt;the Patriot Act&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transportation_Security_Administration&quot;&gt;founding of the TSA&lt;/a&gt;, and the invasion in Iraq under the lie of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iraq_and_weapons_of_mass_destruction&quot;&gt;weapons of mass destruction&lt;/a&gt;. As you see, the claim of fighting drugs as a pretext for militaristic actions within the United States, the subverting of Congress' authority, and the lies and taring of anyone who challenges the lies is a long held Republican tradition. " created="Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:01:16 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="TSA Everywhere" created="Wed, 11 Jun 2025 15:56:24 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I think that a big problem with what is going on in the United States is that for too many citizens they think that what is happening is not going to affect them. Every part of our society is selfish. Only until something affects me will I have a problem with it. So, if as an opponent to the current Republican regime I had a large enough audience on TV or in writing, I would ask people to remember the after math of 9/11 and in particular the creation of the TSA. Do you want more &quot;TSA&quot; everywhere in the country? Remember that up until 9/11 there were not federal officers in every airport making you take off your shoes and go through metal detectors. Before 9/11 you had the freedom to walk directly go to a gate to see your friends and family even if you didn't have a plane ticket! What the current Republican regime is doing is expanding federal officer presence, like the TSA, to more locations through out the country. These people will be armed and wear military gear. More surveillance and less liberty for of all of us under the disguise of catching &quot;illegals.&quot; " created="Wed, 11 Jun 2025 15:02:30 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="Since 9/11 we have become too accepting of these increases in the federal law enforcement and presence in our lives and too accepting of infringements on liberty even to the point where people might even think liberty is not important. The founders of the United States feared a large standing army because of what the Republican regime is now doing. The southern states demanded the second amendment, the right to bear arms, because they feared a president federalizing state militias, the very thing that Trump has done in California. The regime has convince too many citizens to not be awake to what they are doing. Don't be woke they say as they methodically increase the police state, put armed &quot;officers/troops&quot; on every street in the country and take away your first amendment right to protest. " created="Wed, 11 Jun 2025 15:27:07 GMT" type="outline"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 10" created="Tue, 10 Jun 2025 19:31:21 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="10">
				<outline text="As far as I can tell, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/684565/google-pixel-vip-favorite-contacts-availability&quot;&gt;the new Pixel VIPs feature&lt;/a&gt; is supposed to be one of the new things I see with Android 16 but it's not currently available on my Pixel 7a. Basically, Android 16 is just a security update on my phone." created="Tue, 10 Jun 2025 21:09:37 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Just checked for updates on the Pixel 7a and found that &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5google.com/2025/06/10/android-16-june-update-pixel/&quot;&gt;Android 16 is available&lt;/a&gt;. Tapped Download and install. I may be a glutton. " created="Tue, 10 Jun 2025 19:31:22 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 9" created="Mon, 09 Jun 2025 14:12:05 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="09">
				<outline text="Hey, it's &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/06/09/at-wwdc-apple-introduces-ios-26-and-macos-26-in-major-operating-system-rebrand/&quot;&gt;Windows 95 all over again&lt;/a&gt;. What's old is new. " created="Mon, 09 Jun 2025 17:40:10 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="I really fear that we are being baited in to a situation for Trump to declare marshall law in the United States. If you think about why Trump and his billionaire supporters are so focused about immigration I don't see any real benefit for them personally other than knowing it's likely to result in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/internet-censorship/682830/immigration-protests-los-angeles-national-guard-david-huerta-ice&quot;&gt;riots that provide them the pre-text to put the U.S. military on streets&lt;/a&gt;. We will see another &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kent_State_shootings&quot;&gt;Kent State&lt;/a&gt; as the military is taught to shoot first and ask questions later, they are not taught to be a police force. I am very skeptical that Trump and the power behind him really cares of jobs for the middle class and everything they do is about power for themselves. Heck, I expect Trump and many others in his orbit rely heavily on the low cost labor of illegal immigrants. The entire Republican party is taken over by the power grab, it does not care about the Constitution nor liberty nor democracy for anything other than themselves. Everything they do is to redirect attention from themselves and divide any potential opposition. " created="Mon, 09 Jun 2025 15:57:40 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://bun.sh/docs&quot;&gt;Bun&lt;/a&gt; is a drop in replacement for Nodejs on Mac OS. It's a pre-req for running &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/selfire1/llm-markdown-journal-summary?tab=readme-ov-file&quot;&gt;this markdown journalizing summarizer&lt;/a&gt; that uses ollama. " created="Mon, 09 Jun 2025 14:59:53 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Learned about [Widgets for Obsidian](https://apps.apple.com/us/app/widgets-for-obsidian/id6642646117) via [this thread on micro.blog](https://lillihub.com/timeline/66285154#66285154) and installed on the iPad Mini. Created a widget to create a quick note and another to open the ToDo page in my Obisidian vault." created="Mon, 09 Jun 2025 14:12:06 GMT" type="markdown"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 5" created="Thu, 05 Jun 2025 13:08:59 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="05">
				<outline text="&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/my-7-favorite-android-16-features-include-delights-for-every-pixel-user/&quot;&gt;Here is an article&lt;/a&gt; that highlights changes coming with Android 16 that I may notice." created="Thu, 05 Jun 2025 14:46:20 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="Now that I am running my own instance of Feedland I see that it stores everything in MySQL, which seems wrong to me. I am not surprised that the feed information is stored in the database, but I would have expected the rivers to be generated outside of the database. My guess is for this to scale to many users the servers running MySQL need to be pretty large and probably clustered. I've noticed the performance of feedland.org to be pretty slow and while feedland.com, hosted by Wordpress, is better, that is not as fast as my own instance. " created="Thu, 05 Jun 2025 13:22:11 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="It's raining out and it looks like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weather.gov/grb/Smoke&quot;&gt;the Canadian forest fire smoke&lt;/a&gt; has reached us as the AQI is at 156. Sensors directly west of us is at least 10 points higher." created="Thu, 05 Jun 2025 13:09:00 GMT" type="outline"/>
				<outline text="A NotebookLM Notebook Of My Daynotes" created="Thu, 05 Jun 2025 16:06:13 GMT" type="outline">
					<outline text="I've created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://notebooklm.google.com&quot;&gt;Google NotebookLM&lt;/a&gt; notebook for my 2025 day notes. Turns out that how Old School generates monthly index files works well as sources to NotebookLM. All I did was add the URL to the monthly index page, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://oldschool.scripting.com/frank.mcpherson@gmail.com/2025/05/&quot;&gt;this one for May&lt;/a&gt;, as a source to the notebook, and that enables me to ask questions about my writing. I intend to see whether this will work in a manner similar to search for my writing. For now I am not going to share this publicly." created="Thu, 05 Jun 2025 15:48:56 GMT" type="outline"/>
					<outline text="If Google enabled RSS feeds to be a source for NotebookLM and that had the ability to get updates then one could have a notebook in which to be able query their latest writing. I tried using the RSS feed for my micro.blog but that is a JSON file that is not a valid source for NotebookLM. Given that at some point in time Google will monetize NotebookLM, I think it's probable that URL structured data like JSON will be a valid source if you have a subscription. Feeds are a constantly flow of information going in to NotebookLM and processing would like significantly increase Google's operating cost of the product. " created="Thu, 05 Jun 2025 16:00:44 GMT" type="outline"/>
					</outline>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 4" created="Wed, 04 Jun 2025 14:12:26 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="04">
				<outline text="The Cubs beat the Nationals last night and in the game they hit the team's 200,000 hit since the National League was formed in 1876. &lt;a href=&quot;https://readwise.io/reader/shared/01jwxm6s8vcp9ka3g9v94trjtr&quot;&gt;The Cubs are the first NL team&lt;/a&gt; to reach that mark." created="Wed, 04 Jun 2025 14:12:27 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			<outline text="June 2" created="Mon, 02 Jun 2025 17:10:45 GMT" type="calendarDay" name="02">
				<outline text="I don't see the visible line running down the edge of the Boox Go 7 described in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/boox-go-7-review/&quot;&gt;this review&lt;/a&gt;. I think I have my Go 7 set to 70% brightness and the temperature turned all the way off. It might be that my eyes are not sensitive to the line. The main issue that I have is that the touch screen is too sensitive around the edges. Some times when I am holding the Go 7 reading a book the page turns when I do not want it to. " created="Mon, 02 Jun 2025 17:10:46 GMT" type="outline"/>
				</outline>
			</outline>
		</body>
	</opml>
